Guide to the John White Geary Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
John White Geary papers
1855-1871
WA MSS 212
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
1.6
(4 boxes)
The collection consists of the official papers of John Geary while governor of Kansas Territory, 1856-57, with some personal papers, 1855-71. The papers document Kansas during the Free State War and the building of the capitol.
Geary, John White, 1819-1873
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of William Robertson Coe.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Associated Materials
Other Geary collections at the Beinecke are the John White Geary Business Papers (WA MSS 209), the John White Geary Mexican War Papers (WA MSS S-585), and a letter from Geary to Major General Persifor Smith (WA MSS S-218).
Scope and Contents
John White Geary was born near Mount Pleasant, Westmoreland County, Pennsylvania, on December 30, 1819. He served during the Mexican War in the 2d Pennsylvania Infantry. In 1849, President Polk appointed him postmaster at San Francisco, but Geary had hardly begun his duties when his Whig successor, appointed by President Taylor, arrived. Geary was elected first alcalde of San Francisco and appointed judge; he later became the first mayor. In 1852, he returned to Pennsylvania, and in 1856, when Kansas was in a state of civil war, he accepted appointment as governor of the Territory. He made great advances at first, but aroused the enmity of pro-slavery politicians. When he did not receive the necessary military and official support from the government, he resigned and returned to Pennsylvania in 1857. He later served as colonel of the 28th Pennsylvania Regiment during the Civil War and was twice elected governor of the state, serving from 1867 to 1873.
The manuscripts in the John White Geary Papers give a vivid picture of conditions in Kansas during the Free State War. They consist of the "executive minutes" and official correspondence of John W. Geary, Governor of Kansas Territory, 1856-57, as well as a few personal letters and papers, 1855-57. They include petitions from citizens of other states in behalf of the Free State prisoners, congratulatory letters on Geary's accomplishment in restoring peace in Kansas, and documents and receipts relating to the building of the capitol.
The letters from Governor Geary are copies, usually in his secretary's hand. There are typewritten transcripts of some of the more important papers. The correspondence, with the exception of five letters written between 1862 and 1871, is dated from April 22, 1856 to December 4, 1857. The minutes, which are almost all in John Gihon's handwriting, contain copies of official letters to and from the governor, his messages to the legislature, and other official acts, with records of events in diary form inserted chronologically.
The following detailed list of papers in the collection can also be found on pp. 110-24 of A Catalogue of Manuscripts in the Collection of Western Americana in the Yale University Library, Mary C. Withington, editor.
Appendix: Alphabetical List of Correspondents
Geary, John White. Executive minutes kept by Governor Geary's private secretary, John H. Gihon, September 9, 1856-March 20, 1857. 2 vols. [i.e., 533 pp.] Original bindings. 31-33 cm.
The minutes, which are almost entirely in Gihon's handwriting, contain copies of official letters to and from the governor, his messages to the legislature and other official acts, with records of events in diary form inserted chronologically.
---- Governor Geary's personal letters and reports to Secretary of State William L. Marcy, Secretary of the Treasury James Guthrie, President Pierce, and President Buchanan. September 6, 1856-February 12, 1857. Copied by his secretary. 130 pp. Original binding. 20 1/2 cm.
---- Letter to James Buchanan. April 27, 1857. Copy. 3 pp.
---- Two letters to Lewis Cass. April 20, December 4, 1857. Copies. 4 pp.
---- Letter to George W. Clarke. December 22, 1856. Copy. 2 pp.
---- Letter to William Flinn. January 7, 1857. Copy. 2 pp.
---- Letter to John B. Floyd. April 17, 1857. Copy. 2 pp.
---- Letter to John A. Halderman, F. Renick, William A. Shannon, Committee. September 9, 1856. Copy. 1 p.
---- Letter to L. S. Hall. October 11, 1856. Copy. 1 p.
---- Power of attorney to Andrew J. Jones. August 28, 1856. Witnessed by Richard McAllister and Theodore Adams, and signed by Jones before the same witnesses. 3 pp.
---- Letter to the Hon. W. Medill. July 8, 1857. Copy. 1 p.
---- Three letters to Franklin Pierce, President of the United States. August 9-December 10, 1856. Copies. 6 pp.
---- Letter to William P. Richardson. August 21, 1856. Copy. 1 p.
---- Letter to Governor Charles Robinson. July 13, 1857. Copy. 2 pp.
---- Two letters to Persifor F. Smith. October 6, November 11, 1856. Copies. 4 pp.
---- Letter to H. T. Titus. November 8, 1856. Copy. 1 p.
---- Letter to Elisha Whittlesey. February 4, 1857. With statement of account to June 30, 1857. Copy. 2 pp.
---- Abstract of account in disbursement for the capitol. April 16, 1857. 2 copies. 2 pp.
---- Abstract statement of expenditures [ca. July 7, 1856]. 2 copies. 4 pp.
---- Abstract of expenditures in the purchase of library for Kansas Territory [December 1, 1856]. With the receipted bill for the books signed by James L. Gihon, December 2, 1856. 12 pp.
---- Affidavit for the arrest of William T. Sherrard before S. G. Cato, February 9, 1857. Copy. 2 pp.
---- Bill for expenses, September 9, 1856-March 5, 1857. Copy. With unsigned copy of accompanying affidavit, April 16, 1857. 4 pp.
---- Estimate by counties of the probable population of the Territory. November 27, 1856. Copy. 1 p.
---- Memorandum of payments made to Kansas Militia. December 3, 1856. Copy. 1 p.
---- Memorandum of testimony, Territory vs. J. A. W. Jones. February 28, 1857. 1 p.
---- "Opinions & notes." [August 9, 1856.] Not Geary's hand. 1 p.
---- Statement of conditions in Kansas Territory. Endorsed: "Notes prepared by JON." [n.d.] 18 pp.
Abreo, Mrs. Cornelia M. Letter to Geary. December 9, 1856. 2 pp.
Adams, Theodore. 13 letters to Geary. August 22, 1856-July 8, 1857. 28 pp.
Anderson, Robert. Letter to Geary. September 19, 1856. 1 p.
Arny, William F. M. Two letters to Geary. December 8, 1856, February 2, 1857. 12 pp.
"Atcherson County." Letter to Geary about Charles M. Hays. February 6, 1857. Signed: "Atcherson County." 2 pp.
Babcock, Carmi W. Letter to Colonel McAllister. February 16, 1857. 2 pp.
Bachman, B. C. Letter to Geary. March 10, 1857. With noted added from Josephine Stuart. 2 pp.
Bailey, James G. Letter to Geary. October 9, 1856. 2 pp.
Bainter, Ephraim. Territory of Kansas vs. Ephraim Bainter. November 3, 1856. Certiifed copy of judgment, February 17, 1857, James R. Whitehead, clerk, by W. L. Kuykendall, deputy. 2 pp.
Baker, Arthur J. Two letters to Geary. January 12, February 10, 1857. 4 pp.
Banks, E. A. Letter to Geary. January 26, 1857. 1 p.
Bardwell, George H. Letter to Geary. January 19, 1857. 2 pp.
Barnett, Ward B. Letter to Geary. September 26, 1856. 1 p.
Barnum, Heron. Letter to Geary. October 11, 1856. 1 p.
Barton, John T. Letter to Geary. House of Representatives, January 1, 1857. 1 p.
Bashford, Coles. Letter to Geary. November 29, 1856. 1 p.
Beach, Ashael. Letter to Geary. October 4, 1856. 2 pp.
Beeson, Richard. Letter to Geary. October 23, 1856. 2 pp.
Betts, Royston. Letter to Geary. December 31, 1856. 2 pp.
Big Springs. Citizens. Report of a meeting upholding Geary. February 17, 1857. Signed by Charles D. Jones, chairman, Charles A. Allen, secretary, and 22 others. 2 pp.
Bigham, John. Letter to Geary. September 15, 1857. Signed also by Joseph Cook, John B. Davison, George Gallagher. 1 p.
Bigler, William. Two letters and a telegram to Geary. July 23- November 14, 1856. 5 pp.
Bingham, E. F. Letter to Geary. January 15, 1857. 3 pp.
Bingham, George. Letter to Geary. January 24, 1857. 1 p.
Bladen, Washington. Letter to Geary. August 26, 1856. 2 pp.
Boone, Albert G. Letter to Geary. March 5, 1857. 1 p.
Bowman, George W. Three letters to Geary. January 21-March 11, 1857. 6 pp.
Boyle, J. A. Letter to Geary. March 7, 1857. 2 p.
Bradshaw, William. Letter to Geary. August 4, 1856. 1 p.
Breece, S. D. Letter to Geary. September 1, 1856. 1 p.
Bretz, C. Letter to Geary. November 15, 1856. 1 p.
Bright, J. D. Letter to Geary. November 5, 1856. Signature only. 1 p.
Bright, M. G. Letter to Geary. November 7, 1856. 3 pp.
Brindle, William. Four letters to Geary. May 15, 1856- January 17, 1857. 7 pp.
Brookbank, John B. Letter to Geary. September 12, 1856. 1 p.
Brown, George W. Seven letters to Geary. September 1, 1856- January 15, 1857. 13 pp.
Brown, James W. Letter to Geary. February 8, 1857. 1 p.
Browne, O. H. Letter to Geary. September 13, 1856. 2 pp.
Brunswick, Me. Citizens. To the President of the United States. Petition in behalf of prisoners. Endorsed: "Referred to Gov. Geary for any suggestions he may think the case warrants. F. P." [November 1856?] With 30 signatures. 2 pp.
Buchanan, James. Letter to Geary. November 3, 1856. Signature only. 1 p.
Bullock, Charles P. Letter to Geary. January 13, 1857. 2 pp.
Burgess, R. Letter to Geary. January 14, 1857. 6 pp.
Butler, David. Letter to Geary. April 28, 1871. 1 p.
Caldwell, A. Letter to Geary. August 30, 1856. 3 pp.
Calhoun, John. "Proceedings of a meeting said to have been held at Council House, Wyandot." John Calhoun chairman and McLean secretary. Notes in an unidentified hand [July? 1856]. 1 p.
Calohan, William S. Letter to Geary. August 2, 1856. 1 p.
Carpenter, Samuel L. Letter to Geary. January 29, 1857. 2 pp.
Cass, Lewis. Four letters to Geary. October 23, 1856- November 28, 1857. 9 pp.
---- Letter to Hon. Howell Cobb. May 22, 1857. Copy. 1 p.
Castleman, Benjamin D. Letter to Geary. September 16, 1856. 1 p.
Cato, Sterling G. Letter to Geary. November 10, 1856. 2 pp.
Christian, James. Letter to Geary. June 21, 1857. 2 pp.
Clegg, B. Letter to Geary. February 10, 1857. 2 pp.
Coffey, A. M. Letter to Geary. March 7, 1857. Signed also by M. McCaslin. 2 pp.
Coleman, William. Letter to Geary. June 27, 1857. 1 p.
Collins, Thomas. Letter to Geary. January 28, 1857. 1 p.
Cook, William A. Letter to Geary. July 27, 1857. 1 p.
Cooke, Philip St. George. Five letters to Geary. [September 12, 1856]- March 14, 1857. 8 pp.
Corley, John. Letter to Geary. February 3, [1857]. 1 p.
Coyle, John. Three letters to Geary. September 20, 1856- January 26 [i.e., 29], 1857. The letter of September 20 is signed also by William Bryant, Charles King, and J. B. Todd. 6 pp.
Craig, Henry Knox. Letter to Geary. November 13, 1856. 1 p.
Crane, John M. Letter to Geary. November 3, 1856. 2 pp.
Cunard, L. M. Letter to Geary. November 6, 1856. 1 p.
Cunningham, Thomas. Letter to Geary. February 15, 1857. 2 pp.
Curry, William B. Three letters to Geary. August 13- September 3, 1856. 3 pp.
Cushman, C. A. Letter to Geary. September 12, 1856. 2 pp.
Cutler, Andrew S. Two letters to Geary. October 22, 29, 1856. 4 pp.
Danforth, C. H. Letter to Geary. January 12, 1857. 3 pp.
Daniels, Edward. Letter to Geary. December 11, 1856. 2 pp.
Davidson, H. O. Letter to Geary. August 17, 1856. 2 pp.
Davis, B. F. Letter to Geary. February 9, 1857. 4 pp.
Davis, Isaac. Letter to Geary. November 13, 1856. 2 pp.
Davis, John W. Letter to Geary. July 29, 1856. 4 pp.
Delahay, Mark W. Letter to Geary. February 4, 1857. 2 pp.
DeSelding, Charles. Letter to Geary. January 17, 1857. 1 p.
Dewey, S. P. Letter to Geary. August 2, 1856. 2 pp.
DeWolfe, Ezekiel. Letter to Geary. September 7, 1856. 3 pp.
Dick, John T. Letter to Geary. February 16, 1857. 2 pp.
Donoughe, Cornelius. Two letters to Geary. August 9, October 22, 1856. 9 pp.
Dougherty, B. A. Letter to Geary. July 29, 1856. 1 p.
Downer, James P. Three letters to Geary. October 4, 1856- January 30, 1856 [i.e., 1857]. 7 pp.
Drum, Richard C. Letter to Geary. November 3, 1856. 1 p.
Dull, J. J. Two letters to Geary. January 22, February 23, 1857. 3 pp.
Duncan, William M. Letter to Geary. January 30, 1857. 2 pp.
Dundas, William H. Letter to Geary. November 26, 1856. 1 p.
Dunn, Richard C. Letter to Geary. February 17, 1857. 2 pp.
Dutton, Benjamin F. Letter to Geary. July 29, 1856. 1 p.
Dyer, William F. Letter to Geary. January 26, 1857. 1 p.
Eastin, Lucien J. Letter to Geary. February 26, 1857. 2 pp.
Eberhart, A. G. Two letters to Geary. October 30, 1856, February 11, 1857. 3 pp.
Edgar, William. Letter to Geary. November 3, 1856. 2 pp.
Eldridge, Shaler W. Two letters to Geary. December 18, 1856, February 9, 1857. 2 pp.
Elliott, Archibald. Letter to Geary. September 19, 1856. 2 pp.
Elliott, John A. Letter to Geary. January 19, 1857. 2 pp.
Emerson, W. A. G. Letter to Geary. February 12, 1857. 3 pp.
Emory, W. H. Letter to Geary. September 12, 1856. 2pp.
Emrick, Simon. Letter to Geary. February 7, 1857. 1 p.
Fish, Hamilton. Form letter to Geary. April 15, 1871. With a printed copy of the Act of Congress providing for the commemoration of the centennial. 1 p.
Flenniken, Robert P. Letter to Geary. January 15, 1857. 1 p.
Flint, F. F. Letter to Geary. January 27, 1857. 2 pp.
Forman, John W. Petition to Governor Geary. [September, 1856?] Signed also by William P. Richardson, F. J. Marshall, D. A. N. Grover, B. O. Driscoll, and Thomas W. Waterson. 1 p.
Forster, John T. Letter to Geary. January 5, 1857. 3 pp.
Fox, George K. Letter to Geary. June 6, 1857. 1 p.
Frain, William P. Letter to Geary. March 9, 1857. 2 pp.
Friend to the oppressed, A. Letter to Geary. November 21, 1856. 4 pp.
Fuller, Perry. Letter to Geary. March 4, 1857. 2 pp.
Furcey, William. Letter to Geary. February 6, 1857. 1 p.
Garrett, R. Letter to Governor Geary on the division of Riley County. February 16, 1857. Signed also by Thomas Reynolds and Stephen B. Williams. 1 p.
Garvey, Edward C. K. Letter to Geary. November 24, 1856. 1 p.
Gates, Mrs. Louise W. Letter to Geary. February 9, 1857. 2 pp.
Geary, Edward R. Five letters to his brother, John W. Geary. September 17, 1856-February 19, 1857. 18 pp.
Geary, Edward R., 2d. Eight letters to his father, J. W. Geary. June 13, 1856-September 2, 1857. 21 pp.
Geary, John. Letter to his uncle, J. W. Geary. November 1, [1855]. Signed by his mark and written by his father, E. R. Geary, with note added on the same sheet. 2 pp.
George, George W. Letter to Geary. November 3, 1856. 2 pp.
Gihon, John H. 14 letters to Geary. October 28 [i.e., 18], 1856- July 29, 1857. 47 pp.
Gihon, John L. [H?]. Letter to Geary. July 15, 1857. 1 p.
Gilman, Charles. Letter to Geary. October 23, 1856. 4 pp.
Goetsch, Oscar. Letter in German to Geary. January 29, 1857. Signed also by Maria Goetsch. 4 pp.
Goodin, Joel Kishler. Two letters to Geary. February 12, 18, 1857. 4 pp.
Gorley, J. Letter to Geary. November 14, 1856. 2 pp.
Graham, A. D. Letter to Geary. February 28, 1857. 1 p.
Grant, Edwin H. Letter to Geary. July 30, 1857. 4 pp.
Greathouse, J. S. Letter to Geary. January 30, 1857. 2 pp.
Guthrie, John B. Letter to Geary. August 4, 1856. 4 pp.
Haldeman, Cyrus S. Six letters to Geary. November 13, 1856- May 22, [1857]. 14 pp.
Haldeman, Horace. Letter to Geary. February 9, 1857. 3 pp.
Halderman, John A. Two letters to Geary. September 9, 1856, January 20, 1857. The earlier letter is signed also by O. F. Renick and W. A. Shannon. 3 pp.
Hall, L. S. Two letters to Geary. October 10, November 24, [1856]. 4 pp.
Hampton, Levi J. Two letters to Geary. March 16, 23, 1857. 4 pp.
Harvey, John A. Two letters to Geary. November 22, 1856, March 4, 1857. 5 pp.
Hastings, John. Letter to Geary. September 20, 1856. 1 p.
Hatch, J. M. Letter to Geary. April 10, 1857. 3 pp.
Hawke, George. Letter to Geary. February 9, 1857. 2 pp.
Hays, John. Letter to Geary. January 3, 1857. 1 p.
Heberton, Edward P. Letter to Geary. [September 1856.] Enclosing a letter of introduction to Governor Geary from David R. Porter, September 6, 1856. 3 pp.
Heiskell, William A. Letter to Geary. March 5, 1857. Signed also by L. D. Williams. 2 pp.
Heister, A. O. Letter to Geary. September 18, 1856. 1 p.
Henshaw, John C. Letter to Geary. July 29, 1856. 1 p.
Hewitt, Girart. Letter to Geary. November 6, 1856. 3 pp.
Hickory Point, Jefferson Co., K. T. "Names of Convicts who were convicted for acts committed at Hickory Point, Jefferson County, K. T." [October? 1856.] In an unidentified hand. 1 p.
Hicks, Sarah (Mrs. Joseph). Letter to Geary. November 9, 1856, with added note, November 24. 3 pp.
Higgins, Silas Parsons. Letter to Geary. November 29, 1856. 3 pp.
Hodge, William L. Letter to Geary. August 12, 1856. 2 pp.
Holmes, William W. Letter to Geary. January 29, 1857. 1 p.
Hoogland, Edward. 11 letters to Geary. August 18, [1856]- April 19, 1857. 43 pp.
Horrell, Irwin. Letter to Geary. February 16, 1857. Signature only. 2 pp.
Hornsby, Brinkly. Letter to Geary. October 27, 1856. 1 p.
Hoscroft, John I. Letter to Geary. February 16, 1857. 1 p.
Hughes, H. Courtenay. Letter to Geary. January 7, 1857. 1 p.
Hulburd, A. N. Letter to Geary. February 14, 1857. 3 pp.
Hulse, George T. Letter to Geary. March 3, 1857. 1 p.
Humphrey, John. Letter to Geary. February 2, 1857. 2 pp.
Hunter, Alexander Letter to Geary. October 23, 1856. 3 pp.
Hurd, H. B. Two letters to Geary. October 8, November 22, 1856. 3 pp.
Hyatt, Thaddeus. Two letters to Geary. December 5, 8, 1856. Signatures only. 5 pp.
Iowa County, Wis. Citizens. Petition in behalf of William H. Gill. November 8, 1856. With 37 signatures. 3 pp.
Irvine, James. Two letters to Geary. August 10, 1856, January 19, 1857. 6 pp.
Ives, Timothy. Two letters to Geary. October 24, November 5, 1856. 2 pp.
Ivory, William W. Letter to Geary. August 7, 1856. 3 pp.
Jackson, Isaiah H. Letter to Geary. November 6, 1856. 2 pp.
James, Burton A. Two letters to Geary. January 7, February 23, 1857. 2 pp.
James, Henry. Letter to Geary. January 11, 1857. 2 pp.
Jefferson County, K. T. Citizens. Petition in behalf of Ephraim Bainter. [October? 1856.] With 87 signatures. 5 pp.
Jefferson, Ind. Committee. Petition for clemencey for Otis Mason Marsh. November 5, 1856. Signed by Levi Sparks and nine citizens, with a letter from Joseph A. Wright, Governor of Indiana, November 7, 1856. 2 pp.
Johns, Henry F. Letter to Geary. March 30, 1857. 6 pp.
Johnson, James Neely. Letter to Geary. March 18, 1857. Signature only. 1 p.
Johnson, L. M. Letter to Geary. February 3, 1857. 2 pp.
Johnston, B. K. Letter to Geary. September 14, 1856. 2 pp.
Johnstone, Edward. Three letters to Geary. September 14-October 22, 1856. 6 pp.
Jones, A. W. Letter to Geary. December 1, 1856. 1 p.
Jones, Andrew J. 21 letters to Geary. July 21, 1856-July 8, 1857. 47 pp.
Jones, John A. W. Three letters to Geary. October 6, 1856- July 6, 1857. The letter of July 6 encloses a copy of Medill's letter to Jones, July 3, 1857. 8 pp.
Jones, Sarah L. Letter to Geary. January 24, 1857. 2 pp.
Kansas Territory. Citizens. Petition in behalf of William Partridge. December 22, 1856. With 70 signatures. 3 pp.
---- Petition for the release of Free State prisoners, with the names of the prisoners [January 13, 1857]. Signed by G. W. Brown, Richard J. Hinton, James F. Walker, L. S. Hall, A. W. Gleason. 5 pp.
Kansas Territory. Legislature. Committee. Notes of remarks about Geary [by John Calhoun?] during the 3d Session of the House. [After January 12, 1857.] Endorsed by Geary [?]: "This paper was blown by the wind from Surveyor Genl. Calhoun's office to mine." 1 p.
Kean, John. Two letters to Geary. January 25, February 20, 1857. 2 pp.
Kerr, Leander. Letter to Geary. October 23, 1856. 3 pp.
Key, Thomas K. Two letters to Geary. January 26, February 20, 1857. 4 pp.
Killen, Daniel. Letter to Geary. March 8, 1857. Signed, with postscript by Killen. 1 p.
King, Horatio. Letter to Geary. October 29, 1856. 2 pp.
King, John A. Letter to Geary. January 9, 1857. 3 pp.
Kirkpatrick, John M. Four letters to Geary. August 23, 1856- April 2, 1857. 10 pp.
Klotz, Robert. Letter to Geary. March 25, 1857. 1 p.
Ladd, Erastus D. Letter to Geary. January 30, 1857. 3 pp.
Ladies Sewing Circle, Lawrence. Invitation to Geary. November 14, 1856. Signed by L. S. Hall, corresponding secretary. 1 p.
Laird, J. M. Letter to Geary. January 10, 1857. 3 pp.
Lanz, Alfred. Letter to Geary. February, 1857. 1 p.
---- Petition for pardon for men convicted for their part in the attack on Hickory Point. [n.d., October ? 1856.] Signed also by J. M. Bernard, W. W. Spratt, D. K. Stout, M. P. Randall, Matthew R. Walker, G. N. Reis. 1 p.
Latham, R. W. Letter to Geary. January 22, 1857. 2 pp.
Lawrence, Amos A. Two letters to Geary. November 8, 1856, February 5, 1857. 3 pp.
Leavitt, Stephen. Letter to Geary. January 8, 1857. 1 p.
LeCompte, Samuel Dexter. Letter to Geary. September 17, 1856. 3 pp.
Lloyd, William M. Letter to Geary. October 9, 1856. 1 p.
Logan, Samuel. Letter to his brother-in-law, J. W. Geary. June 23, 1856. 1 p.
Logan, William W. Three letters to Geary. July 9-August 5, 1856. 4 pp.
Lowry, M. B. Letter to Geary. July 30, 1856. Signature only. 2 pp.
McAleer, Joseph L. Letter to Geary. January 9, 1857. 1 p.
McAllister, John H. Letter to Geary. December 6, 1856. 4 pp.
McAllister, Richard. Nine letters to Geary. July 14, 1856- May 13, 1857. 28 pp.
McCandless, Wilson. Letter to Geary. September 19, 1856. 1 p.
McCann, Thomas K. Three letters to Geary. July 31, 1856- March 27, 1857. 8 pp.
McCaslin, Maxwell. Seven letters to Geary. August 9, 1856- February 25, 1857. 17 pp.
McClintock, Jonas R. Letter to Geary. [n.d.] Endorsed: "August 1, 1856." 1 p.
McFadin, Andrew H. Three letters to Geary about Henry Sherman. March 3-9, 1857. The last letter is signed also by L. D. Williams, Henry Tuley, Thomas Totten, George Wilson and S. P. Boon before Henry W. Peck. 4 pp.
McFarren, Samuel. Letter to Geary. February 4, 1857. 2 pp.
McGee, E. M. Letter to Geary. January 10, 1857. 3 pp.
McKowen, Samuel. Two letters to Geary. October 8, 1856, February 16, 1857. 3 pp.
McLure, C. C. Letter to Geary. September 9, 1856. 1 p.
McNamara, Thomas. Two letters to Geary. October 16, 1856, February 23, 1857. 5 pp.
McQuaide, James G. Letter to Geary. September 15, 1856. 2 pp.
Maguire, Thomas A. Two letters to Geary. August 6, September 14, 1856. 2 pp.
Marcy, William Learned. Two letters to Geary. August 26, September 2, 1856. Signatures only. 5 pp.
Markoe, Francis. Three letters to Geary. August 8-October 24, 1856. 4 pp.
Marsh, Samuel. Two letters to Geary. October 13, 1856. Enclosing a letter of the same date to his brother, Otis Mason Marsh. 4 pp.
---- Letter to President Pierce. October 13, 1856. Endorsed: "Referred to Gov. Geary. F. P." 1 p.
Marshall, Frank J. Letter to Geary. September 16, 1856. 2 pp.
---- Agreement with Governor Shannon to transport from St. Louis material for the capitol at Lecompton, April 22, 1856. Signed by Marshall and Wilson Shannon, witnessed by R. C. Bishop, C. A. Perry, Elias H. Perry, and H. Basye. Copy. 3 pp.
---- Receipt for transporting material for the capitol. January 13, 1857. Certified by Wilson Shannon. 1 p.
Marye, Simon B. Letter to Geary. August 15, 1856. 3 pp.
Mathias, William G. Letter to Geary. February 18, 1857. 1 p.
Matteson, Joel Aldrich. Letter to Geary. December 25, 1856. Signature only. 1 p.
Maynadier, Henry. Letter to Geary. March 19, 1857. Signature only. 1 p.
Medary, Samuel. Letter to Geary. January 22, 1857. 1 p.
Medill, William. Three letters to Geary. May 27-July 17, 1857. Signatures only. 6 pp.
Merrill, Abel. Letter to Geary. January 13, 1857. 3 pp.
Millar, I. Letter to Geary. November 16, 1856. 1 p.
Miller, George W. Letter to Geary. February 11, 1857. 2 pp.
Mitchell, A. M. Letter to Geary. January 7, 1857. 1 p.
Mitchell, D., Jr. Letter to Geary. February 4, 1856 [i.e., 1857]. 3 pp.
Mitchell, Edward P. Letter to Geary. October 25, 1862. 1 p.
Mitchell, James. Two letters to Geary. November 7, December 12, 1856. 3 pp.
Montague, Isaac W., and Hannah S. Letter to Geary. October 17, 1856. 1 p.
Moore, J. D. Letter to Geary. February 24, 1857. 1 p.